Hopefully, you had a chance to experiment with using different intents
但愿你可以用不同的 intent 来实验一下
from the Common Intents guide.
从 Common Intents guide 文件
For example, I showed you earlier that I modified the submitOrder method.
例如 之前我讲过的更改 submitOrder 方法
I commented out all the existing code and then, added the maps intent code.
我注释掉了所有已经完成的代码 加入地图的 intent 代码
When I run the map on my device, when I click on the order button, instead of
当我在设备上运行应用时 点击 ORDER 按钮
uploading the order summary, it'll actually send an intent to the maps app.
没有更新 ORDER SUMMARY 实际上它给地图应用发送了一个 intent
The Google Maps app receives the intent and then updates the map to show
Google Maps 应用接受了这个 intent 并在地图上更新
the location that we requested in the intent.
我们请求的位置
Even if using these intents doesn't make sense in the context of our coffee
尽管使用这些 intent 对我们咖啡订购的应用没有什么意义
ordering app, It's a good place to practice creating intents.
但是这是练习创建 intent 的好地方
Let's undo this change and then get back to our real tasks.
让我们撤销这个修改 返回我们的实际任务中
In order to add this feature to our app,
为了把这个特性加入到我们的应用中
we need to use an intent to send the order summary to an email app.
我们需要使用一个 intent 将 ORDER SUMMARY 发送到一个 email 应用中
If you had no idea how to accomplish this, you could do a web search.
如果你不知道如何完成这个 你可以上网搜索
I did a search for email intent android.
我就做了一个 email intent android 的搜索
A bunch of useful links pop up like a Stack Overflow post and a tutorial.
一堆有用的链接弹出 像 Stack Overflow 的帖子和一个教程
But the common intents guide pops up and says it's from the official
但 Common intents 教程弹出 这是来自官方的
Android Documentation, I'm going to click on that.
Android Documentation 我计划点击这个
In the side by here there's a link on how to create an email intent,
在里面的这个位置有一个如何创建 email intent 的链接
so I'm going to click on that, this shows you how to send
所以我计划点击这个 这将展示
an intent to compose an email with optional attachments.
如何发送 intent 来构成一个可选附件的 email
Looking through the documentation there are two code examples.
浏览文件 这有两段代码例子
After reading this comment we want this second code example.
读完这个注释 选第二个例子
This is because we want our intent to be handled only by an email app and
这是因为我们希望我们的 intent只能通过 email 应用
not by a text messaging or social media app.
不是通过文本信息或社交媒体软件
Let's select this code and copy it,
让我们选择这段代码并复制
and then we're going to paste it into our app.
粘贴到我们的应用上
Looking at the code for
看一下这段代码
our just Java app where should we actually paste this code snippet?
我们的 JustJava 应用 应该把代码粘贴到哪呢?
Well, we want to send the order summary off to the email app
我们希望给 email 应用发送一个 ORDER SUMMARY 在
as soon as we have the complete order summary.
在一完成 ORDER SUMMARY 的时候
And the place that we have the complete order summary is after this line of code
完成 ORDER SUMMARY 的地方就是这行代码之后
here which creates the order summary and
这行代码就是创建 ORDER SUMMARY 的
then stores it in a string variable called priceMessage.
把它存储到一个叫 priceMessage 的字符串变量中
So I'm going to add a new line here, and then insert our code.
所以我打算在这加一行 插到我们代码中
Notice how we're creating a new intent object
注意我们如何创建一个新的对象
using the constructor with the new keyword in java.
在Java语言中用一个带有 new 关键词的构造函数
We're passing in one argument as input into the constructor
我们给构造函数传入一个参数
to initialize this intent object.
来初始化这个 intent 对象
The argument is this constant called Intent.ACTION_SENDTO.
这个变量是个常量 叫做 Intent.ACTION_SENDTO
Remember the convention is that when you see something in all caps in Java
记住有个惯例 在 Java 里看见的全是大写字母的变量
it means it's a constant.
就意味着它是常量
A constant is a variable who's contents should never change once it's set.
常量是一个一旦内容设定就不能更改的变量
In this case when we're creating our intent
此时 当我们创建我们的 Intent 时
we're using official intent action.
我们使用的是官方的 Intent 动作
ACTION_SENDTO which is defined as a constant in the intent class.
ACTION_SENDTO 被定义为一个 Intent 类的常量
Then we call some methods on this newly created intent object.
然后我们对这个新创建的 Intent 对象调用一些方法
We set the data to be a URI of this format,
将数据设置为这种格式的 URI
"mailto:", that way all the email apps will handle this intent.
"mailto:" 这样所有 email 应用都可以处理这个 intent了
Then we add some extra data into the intent.
然后向 intent 中添加其它的数据
We don't need to specify the two field of this e-mail so
我们不需要在 e-mail 里指明这两个字段
I'm just going to delete that line.
所以 只需删除这一行
We do, however, want to specify the subject of the e-mail message.
然而 我们确实希望指明 e-mail 的信息主题
So I'm going to replace this with actual subject line.
所以我打算用实际的主题替换这行
Just Java order for, and then add the persons name.
Just Java order for 后面接人名
Then these next couple of lines of code check if there's an activity
紧接着这两行是检查设备上是否有 activity
on the device to handle this intent.
来处理这个 intent
If there is then it's safe to send the intent and
如果有 那么发送 intent 是安全的
recall start activity using this intent.
并调用这个 intent 召唤开启 activity
If there's no activity on the device to handle the intent,
如果这里没有 activity 在设备上来处理 intent
then we skip this block of code and we skip sending the intent.
那么我们跳过这部分代码并跳过发送 intent 的过程
Now, let's run the app on our device.
现在让我们在设备上运行一下应用
Now when I click on the order button,
现在点击 ORDER 按钮
it sends an intent to an email app on the device.
它把 intent 发送给一个 email 应用
By default, the Gmail app is going to handle this intent.
默认的 这个 Gmail应用将会处理这个 intent
In a code since I specified a custom subject line, it shows up here as just
因为我制定了一个自定义的主题行代码 在这里显示为Just
Java order for Kaptain Kanal, which is the name that I entered into the app.
Java order for Kaptain Kanal 这是我输入应用的名称
Now, the original quiz question asked us to populate the email subject line,
现在原始问题是要求我们填入 email 的主题行
as well as the message body with the order summary.
还有信息主体里的ORDER SUMMARY
So let's go do that now.
所以现在我们就开始吧
Looking back the the documentation for
回顾一下有关
the email intent, I'm going to scroll up to look at the intent extras.
email intent 的文档 我打算向上滚动看一下 Intent Extra
We need to add an intent extra for
我们需要添加一个 Intent Extra 给
each additional piece of information we want to provide about the email.
每一条我们希望提供给 email 的额外信息
For example, we could have an intent extra about the recipients of the email
例如 我们可以使用一个 intent extra 记录收件人邮箱
And we can have an Intent.EXTRA about the subject line of the email.
而且我们也有一个 Intent.EXTRA 记录邮箱的标题
But this is what we really want.
但这是我们真正需要的
We want to add an Intent.EXTRA to specify the body of the email.
我们需要添加一个 Intent.EXTRA 来明确 email 的正文
Again, Intent.EXTRA_TEXT is a constant defined in the intent java class.
再次说明 Intent.EXTRA_TEXT 是 intent里的 java 类的常量
If I click on it you'll see more information.
如果我点击它 你会看到更多信息
It's defined as a string in the intent class.
它在 intent 类里定义为一个字符串
And the constant value is this string right here.
值即为里面的字符串
In the Just Java app when we create the intent And we're going to populate this
在 Just Java 应用里当我创建一个 intent 并且填入
extra, containing the body of the email message.
Extra 里面包含 email 信息的正文
When the email app receives the intent, they'll know to check for
当 email 应用接收了 intent 他们会检查
this intent extra to find the body of email and then they can populate that.
这个 intent extra 来寻找 email 的正文 然后填入正文
Into the user interface.
进入用户界面
Let's make that code change now.
让我们修改一下代码
I'm going to select this line of code,
选中这行代码
that puts one extra into the intent for the subject of the email.
根据email 的主题 把一个 extra 放进 intent 里
On the next line, I'm going to paste the code.
下一行 我打算粘贴这些代码
Now we're putting a second extra into the intent.
现在我向 intent 里存放第二个 extra
The extra is going to correspond to Intent.EXTRA_TEXT so
extra 与 Intent.EXTRA_TEXT 是相统一的
that we know that it's for the body of the email.
我们了解到这是 email 的正文
The second argument to this method is going to be the actual
第二个函数参数是用来存放
body of the email.
实际的 email 正文的
The body of the email should just contain the order summary and
email 正文应该包含 ORDER SUMMARY
that's sorted in price message so I can just copy this variable over to here.
这是在 priceMessage 中分过类的 所以可以把这个变量复制到这
To recap, for
总的来说
the intent object we're calling a method putExtra to specific the email subject.
对于 intent 对象 我们调用 putExtra 方法来明确 email 的主题
In the same intent object we're calling the put extra method again
对于相同的 intent 对象 我们再次调用函数 putExtra方法
to specify the body of the email.
来明确 email 的正文
And the body of the email is the order summary.
email 的正文就是 OEDER SUMMARY
Now let's run the app on our device.
在设备上运行一下应用
once I complete order, I can click the button to submit.
一旦订单完成 我点击这个按钮提交订单
We send an intent to the email app with the email subject populated and
我们给带有主题的 email 应用发送一个 intent
the summary shows up now.
订单详情出现了
Woo hoo!
哇！
For the third step of this task we're going to remove the code that displays
这个任务的第三步 我们计划移除这个代码
the order summary in the Just Java app because
在 Just Java 中显示订单汇总
now it's going to show up in the email app.
因为现在它将在 email 应用中显示
I'm going to start by modifying the activity main layout to remove the order
我将通过修改 activity_main 布局文件开始移除
summary text views.
ORDER SUMMARY 的TextView
At the bottom of the layout, I'm going to delete the header
在布局文件的底部 我计划删除这个声明头
as well as the TextView that would show the actual order summary.
同时还有显示实际 ORDER SUMMARY 的 TextView
I'm going to save that and switch to the Java file.
保存并转到 Java 文件
In the main activity Java file, I no longer need this display message method,
在 main_activity Java 文件里 我不再需要 displayMessage 方法
which would update the order summary text view because this view with this
它是用来更新 ORDER SUMMARY 的 TextView 的 因为以这个 ID 名称的 View
ID doesn't exist anymore.
不存在了
Since I deleted the display message method, Android studio now gives me
因为我删除了这个 displayMessage 方法 Android studio 现在给我
an error saying that this method doesn't exist, so I'm going to delete this.
错误提示 说这个方法不存在了 所以我打算删除它
Looking back at our code, this makes sense because when we click on the order
回顾我们的代码 这很合理 因为当我们点击这个 ORDER
button, It's going to call the submit order method,
按钮时 它会调用 SubmitOrder 方法
we're going to do all this code, which also sends an intent to the email app.
我打算完成所有的代码 这也将发送给 email一个intent
There's no need to display the order summary within our app any more.
我们的应用里不需要显示 ORDER SUMMARY 了
Let's verify that the app still works.
让我们确认一下应用仍然工作
When you delete large amounts of code,
当你删除大量代码后
it's easier to check immediately that it works and
这更容易即刻检查它是否工作正常
undo the changes if there's a mistake, rather than trying to find it out later.
如果有错误就撤销修改 而不是过后再寻找错误
And the app still works.
应用仍然运作正常
Nice job.
干的漂亮
You added an intent to the just Java app.
你刚刚给 Just Java 应用添加了一个 intent
Intents are one of the core parts of Android, but there are still many more
intent 是 Android 的重要核心组件之一 但也有更多
Android components that can help you build better apps.
Android 组件可以帮你构建更好的应用
I recommend that you check those out on your own after you finish this course.
我推荐在完成这个课程后 你自己学习一下